Inventory of the Percy L. Greaves papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Percy L. Greaves papers
1939-1988
2000C98
Hoover Institution Archives
19 manuscript boxes (7.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, notes, testimony, interview transcripts, reports, and printed matter, relating to the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, and to laissez-faire economics.
Greaves, Percy L.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American economist; minority counsel, Joint Congressional Committee on the Investigation of the Pearl Harbor Attack, 1945-1946.
Scope and Content of Collection
Percy Greaves was active in the 1946 congressional review of the circumstances and lack of preparedness during the Pearl Harbor Attacks of 1941. Relating to this matter, Greaves had collected large amounts of evidence regarding the leadup to the attacks on December 7th, 1941. This evidence includes diplomatic messages between the U.S. and Japan, as well as military documents such as estimates of Japanese force strengths in the Pacific Ocean Region. Additionally, Greaves was a Laissez Faire economist and his papers include correspondence and published works pertaining to economic matters such as fiscal and monetary policy during the cold war era.
United States. Congress. Joint Committee on the Investigation of the Pearl Harbor Attack.; Laissez-faire.; Pearl Harbor (Hawaii), Attack on, 1941.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
- Memoranda and Correspondence Relating to Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1941-1945 (Text 1, Folder 1)
- Materials and Evidence Regarding Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1941 (Text 1, Folder 2)
- Exhibits from Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1941 (Text 1, Folder 3)
- Intercepted Japanese Messages, 1941 (Text 1, Folder 4-5)
- Correspondence, Evidence, and Statements Regarding Pearl Harbor and Investigation, 1941-1946 (Text 2, Folder 1)
- Mixed Contents Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1941-1946 (Text 2, Folder 2)
- Collected Materials on Pearl Harbor Attacks and Investigation, 1941-1946 (Text 2, Folder 3-6)
- John Toland Correpsondence and Reports Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1941-1980 (Text 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence Regarding Economics, 1964-1983 (Text 3, Folder 2)
- Japanese Intercepts from the Corregidor, 1929-1942 (Text 3, Folder 3)
- Collected Materials on Pearl Harbor, 1945-1946 (Text 3, Folder 4)
- News Reports from Pearl Harbor, 1941 (Text 3, Folder 5)
- Station Logs from M + H, 1941 (Text 3, Folder 6)
- Spiral Notebooks, 1962-1964 (Text 3, Folder 7)
- Safford - Barnes Correspondence, 1962 (Text 4, Folder 1)
- Greaves - Safford Correspondence, 1967 (Text 4, Folder 2)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1948-1984 (Text 4, Folder 3)
- J.T. Flynn - Greaves Correspondence, 1946 (Text 4, Folder 4)
- Gary North Interview, 1984 (Text 4, Folder 5)
- Materials Relating to General George Marshall, 1950s (Text 4, Folder 6)
- Admiral Kimmel's Papers, 1958-1963 (Text 4, Folder 7)
- Institute for Historical Review Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Text 4, Folder 8)
- Hiles - Greaves Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Text 4, Folder 9)
- Charles Beard Correspondence and Documents, 1945 (Text 4, Folder 10)
- Ralph Briggs Interviews, Correspondence, and Documents, 1977-1988 (Text 4, Folder 11)
- Memoranda on Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1946 (Text 5, Folder 1)
- Collected Materials Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1940s (Text 5, Folder 2)
- Order of Proof and List of Witnesses, Explanatory Memoranda, 1946 (Text 5, Folder 3)
- World News Pieces, 1942 (Text 5, Folder 4)
- Adm. Kimmel Correspondence and Documents, 1950s (Text 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1944-1965 (Text 5, Folder 6-7)
- Pearl Harbor Project - Adm H. Kimmel, USN, 1949-1950 (Text 5, Folder 8)
- Adm. Kimmel Correspondence with Graves, 1949-1950 (Text 5, Folder 9)
- Seattle Speech on Pearl Harbor, 1949-1950 (Text 5, Folder 10)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1952-1982 (Text 6, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence Regarding Progressive Calvinism League, 1956 (Text 6, Folder 5)
- Collected Materials Regarding Pearl Harbor Attacks, 1940-1959 (Text 6, Folder 6)
- Pearl Harbor Investigation Materials, 1946 (Text 6, Folder 7)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1977-1984 (Text 7, Folder 1-2)
- Collected Materials Regarding Economics, Monetary, Fiscal Policy, 1953-1984 (Text 7, Folder 3-4)
- Correspondence, Lectures, Printed Materials, 1944-1952 (Text 7, Folder 5)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1946-1981 (Text 8, Folder 1)
- Inter-Office Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Text 8, Folder 2)
- Foundation for Economic Education Documents, 1953 (Text 8, Folder 3)
- Republican National Committee Research and Correspondence, 1940s (Text 8, Folder 4)
- Manuscript Review for Thomas Norton, 1948-1949 (Text 8, Folder 5)
- Flynn/O'Connor - Greaves Correspondence Regarding Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1945-1946 (Text 8, Folder 6)
- Ivan Bierly - Greaves Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Text 8, Folder 7)
- Dr. Harry Barnes - Greaves Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Text 8, Folder 8)
- Dr. Hobart Dickinson - Greaves Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Text 8, Folder 9)
- Howard Kirschner - Greaves Correspondence, 1950s (Text 8, Folder 10)
- Collected Material, 1979-1983 (Text 9, Folder 1)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1948-1983 (Text 9, Folder 2)
- Mixed Correspondence, 1949-1983 (Text 9, Folder 3-5)
- Republican National Committee Documents on FDR, 1940s (Text 9, Folder 6)
- Writings on Roosevelt Administration, 1940s (Text 9, Folder 7)
- William Volker - Greaves Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Text 9, Folder 8)
- Newspaper Clippings Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1959-1961 (Text 10, Folder 1)
- Pearl Harbor - Hewett Investigation Notes, 1940s (Text 10, Folder 2)
- News, Correspondence, Printed Materials Regarding Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 10, Folder 3)
- Interviews Regarding Pearl Harbor Attacks, 1945-1980 (Text 10, Folder 4)
- Review of Japanese-American Diplomatic Relations Pre-Pearl Harbor, 1940s (Text 10, Folder 5)
- Reports and Correspondence Regarding Pearl Harbor Attacks, 1960-1975 (Text 10, Folder 6-7)
- Correspondence with National Review, 1966-1967 (Text 11, Folder 1)
- Neumann - Greaves Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Text 11, Folder 2)
- Revisionism Correspondence, 1969 (Text 11, Folder 3)
- Interview with Captain Rochefort, 1941 (Text 11, Folder 4)
- Lewis Rock Correspondence, 1962 (Text 11, Folder 5)
- G.W. Seavers Correspondence and Report, 1960s (Text 11, Folder 6)
- Notes on Pearl Harbor Attacks, 1940s (Text 11, Folder 7)
- Adm. Hart Notes and Correspondence, 1960s (Text 11, Folder 8)
- Institute for Historical Review Correspondence, Undated (Text 11, Folder 9)
- Adm. Shefroth Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Text 11, Folder 10)
- Stimson Notes and Correspondence, Undated (Text 11, Folder 11)
- Collected Materials (Correspondence, News Clippings, Printed Materials), Undated (Text 11, Folder 12-13)
- Harry Barnes - Greaves Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Text 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Documents Regarding Pearl Harbor Attacks, 1940s (Text 12, Folder 2)
- Reports, Correspondence Relating to Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 12, Folder 3)
- Commander Hiles, USN, Documents on Pearl Harbor, 1960s (Text 12, Folder 4-5)
- Journal of Historical Review, 1960s (Text 12, Folder 6)
- Office of Naval Intelligence Reports pre-Pearl Harbor, 1940-1941 (Text 13, Folder 1)
- Pearl Harbor Investigation Evidence, 1940-1946 (Text 13, Folder 2)
- Pearl Harbor Reports for Investigation, 1940-1946 (Text 13, Folder 3)
- Intelligence Reports and Evidence for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940-1946 (Text 13, Folder 4)
- Pearl Harbor Investigation Notes, 1940-1946 (Text 14, Folder 1)
- Capt. Saffold, USN, Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Text 14, Folder 2)
- Adm. Kimmel, USN, Correspondence, 1940s (Text 14, Folder 3)
- Evidence for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1941-1945 (Text 15, Folder 1-3)
- Report on U.S.-Japanese Relations, 1940 (Text 15, Folder 4)
- Henry Stimson Statment to Congress on Pearl Harbor, 1946 (Text 15, Folder 5)
- Evidence for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 16, Folder 1-6)
  - Adm. Kimmel, USN, Testimony in Congress, 1946 (Text 17, Folder 1)
  - Evidence, Memoranda, Correspondence, Notes Regarding Pearl Harbor and Investigation, 1940-1946 (Text 17, Folder 2)
  - Dispatches, Documents, Regarding Pearl Harbor, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 1)
  - Narrative Statements for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1946 (Text 18, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Documents and Memoranda on Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 3)
  - Copies of Defense Plans, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 4)
  - Army Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 5)
  - Evidence and Exhibits for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 6)
  - Secretary of State Cordell Hull Statements for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1940s (Text 18, Folder 7)
  - US War Plans, 1940-1941 (Text 19, Folder 1)
  - Documents and Notes for Pearl Harbor Investigations, 1940s (Text 19, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum on Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1946 (Text 19, Folder 3)
  - Basic Exhibit Dispatches for Pearl Harbor Investigation, 1946 (Text 19, Folder 4)
  - USPACFLEET Rainbow Five Plan, 1940s (Text 19, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Records-House, Freedom of Speech, 1941 (Text 19, Folder 6)